Guide to the South Africa Historical Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory, 1802-1961
  - Photographs
    - Loose (not in albums)
      - Second World War [collection of photographs of mainly South African forces and their leaders in North Africa, Italy, Kenya], Circa 1940-1944 (Box 11, Folder 177)
    - Stereoscopic photographs
      - "The South African War Through the Stereoscope"
        - Photographs nos. 1-60, 1900 (Box 12)
        - Photographs nos. 61-120, 1900-1901 (Box 13)
        - Photographs nos. 121-180, 1901 (Box 14)
        - Photographs nos. 181-216, 1901 (Box 15)
        - "South African War Through the stereoscope" [original cover], undated (Box 16)
      - Boer War [photographs not duplicated in "South Africa War Through the Stereoscope"], 1900-1902 (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous [mining, fishing, daily life, portraits, etc.], [ca.1900], undated (Box 18)
    - Negatives [unidentified people, places], undated (Box 19)
    - Albums
      - Views of Cape Town, Bloemfontein, [ca. 1880-1900?] (Box 20, Folder 178)
      - "Views of Ascension" [island], [ca.1880-1900?] (Box 20, Folder 179)
      - Pretoria and Johannesburg [view of; occupation of territories during Boer War], Circa 1899-1902 (Box 20, Folder 180)
      - "E. E. Caney's Views of Transvaal and South Africa", Circa 1888-1890 (Box 20, Folder 181)
      - "South African Gold Fields: Panoramic and Other Views of Johannesburg", 1889 (Box 21, Folder 182)
      - Plate photographs of South Africa [48 of various South African locations as well as miscellaneous ads and clippings], Circa 1890-1899 (Box 21, Folder 183)
      - Ravenscroft, T. R. [captioned topographical views of Pretoria, Johannesburg, and others], Circa 1890s (Box 21, Folder 184)
      - Rustenburg, [ca. 1890s] (Box 21, Folder 185)
      - "Photographs of South Africa: Comprising Representative Views", 1894 (Box 21, Folder 186)
      - Knaggs, C. J., "Souvenir Views of Pietermaritzburg", Circa 1897 (Box 21, Folder 187)
      - Mining, factories, quarries, dams [unidentified], [ca. 1897?] (Box 22, Folder 188)
      - Middlebrook, J. E., "South African Souvenir", 1898 (Box 22, Folder 189)
      - Photographs from the H. M. Transport "St. Andrew" during the Boer War and China Expedition [South Africa, St. Helena; presumably belonging to A. Weston Jarvis], 1899-1901 (Box 22, Folder 190)
        See also: Inventory, 1802-1961 Box
      - Boer War [British military photographs], Circa 1899-1902 (Box 23, Folder 191)
      - Boer War [album and loose photographs taken by unidentified British officer], Circa 1899-1902 (Box 24, Folder 192)
      - Boer War [photographs taken by unidentified civilian], Circa 1899-1903 (Box 24, Folder 193)
      - Boer War [album of small, captioned photographs apparently compiled by a British solider with headings such as "Trek Zandspruit to Wakkerstroom," "Trek to Utrecht," "Vryheid," etc.], 1899-1902 (Box 24, Folder 194)
      - Scowcroft, H. E. [surgeon's photographs taken in Natal of hospital scenes, Boer refugees, a Kaffir wedding, etc. and one loose pencil drawing], Circa 1900 (Box 25, Folder 195)
      - Middlebrook, J. E., "A Hurried Look Round Durban" [whimsical photo tour of Durban], 1902 (Box 25, Folder 196)
      - "Pictorial Views of St. Helena and Illustrations of the Military Camps and Boer Prisoners of War", Circa 1902 (Box 25, Folder 197)
      - "A Souvenir of King William's Town" [views of the roads, buildings, and nearby scenic spots], Circa 1902 (Box 25, Folder 198)
      - South Africa and Zimbabwe [a few of Zanzibar, Mozambique; 2 volumes], 1903 (Box 25, Folder 199 - 200)
      - Cape Colony, South Africa [family's travel album, town and country scenes, soldiers, Kaffirs; mainly photos of New Zealand], Circa 1903-1912 (Box 26, Folder 201)
      - "Souvenir of the Great Bloemfontein Disaster: An Album of Realist Photographs With Full Descriptions of the Catastrophe" [pp 7-10 missing], 1904 (Box 26, Folder 202)
      - "A Souvenir of Durban", Circa 1910 (Box 26, Folder 203)
      - Towns, native huts, landscapes and game, some Eastern Africa?, Circa 1910 (Box 26, Folder 204)
      - Tourist photos and souvenir cards from the voyage of the "Toledo" [mainly West Africa and Nigeria], 1930 (Box 26, Folder 205)
      - Western Africa [Ghana, Winneba, Appam, probably others as well; includes loose photographs], undated (Box 27, Folder 206)
      - "Natives: Their Homes and Customs" [Zulu men and women in their villages], undated (Box 27, Folder 207)
      - "General Views of South Africa" [etchings of South Africa's main cities and attractions], undated (Box 27, Folder 208)
      - "Barnett's Album of Johannesburg and Surroundings" [The New Collotype Album of Picturesque Views], undated (Box 27, Folder 209)
      - "Barnett's Views of Johannesburg, Cape Town and Pretoria [etchings], undated (Box 27, Folder 210)
      - "Views from Bloemfontein", undated (Box 27, Folder 211)
      - "Coch's Views of Johannesburg", undated (Box 27, Folder 212)
      - "Album of Photographs of Aliwal North, South Africa", undated (Box 27, Folder 213)
  - Oversize
    - Printed materials, drawings, maps
      - Au Transvaal [illustrated supplement by H. Meyer of Dr. Jameson, a prisoner of the Boers], 1896 January 19 (Box 27, Folder 214)
      - Musical scores pertaining to campaigns of the Boer War, Circa 1899-1902 (Box 27, Folder 215)
      - Colored prints depicting the South African War, Circa 1900 (Box 27, Folder 216)
      - Pamphlet published by the authority of Lord Kitchener for the information of the Burghers [includes proclamation, letters, captured letters], 1901 (Box 28, Folder 217)
      - "Thrilling Incidents in English History" [African campaign scenes (1868-1900): illustrations and text], Circa 1902-1900 (Box 28, Folder 218 - 219)
      - Johnston, D. A. [maps from his estate concerning the Transvaal], 1906 (Box 28, Folder 220)
        See also: Inventory, 1802-1961 Folder 64 - 65
      - "A Souvenir of the Visit of the British Association for the Advancement of Science to South Africa" [drawings by Charles E. Peers], 1929 (Box 28, Folder 221)
      - "Harbour Day" [souvenir of the opening of Port Elizabeth Harbour], 1933 (Box 28, Folder 222)
    - Photographs, loose
      - Boer War [photographs taken from both the Boer and British sides, many with captions describing the exact sites and/or persons involved in the conflict; collected by Underwood & Underwood, the stereoscopic print maker company; historical record of the Boer War when photo journalism was just beginning], 1899-1902 (Box 29, Folder 223)
      - Boer War [photographs taken from both the Boer and British sides, many with captions describing the exact sites and/or persons involved in the conflict; collected by Underwood & Underwood, the stereoscopic print maker company; historical record of the Boer War when photo journalism was just beginning], 1899-1902 (Box 30, Folder 224)
      - Battle of Spioenkop, 1900 (Box 31, Folder 225)
      - Kimberley, military hospital, 1900 (Box 31, Folder 226)
      - S. S. "Fort Salisbury", undated (Box 31, Folder 227)
      - Pietermaritzburg, Natal, Namibia [4 loose sheets from album], undated (Box 31, Folder 228)
    - Albums
      - Alexander, Sam, "Photographic Scenery of South Africa", 1880 (Box 32, Folder 229)
      - Harris, Robert, "South Africa Illustrated by a Series of One Hundred and Four Permanent Photographs" [includes 2 loose negatives], 1888 (Box 33, Folder 230)
      - Boer War [British military photographs], 1889-1902 (Box 34, Folder 231)
      - Private collection of photographs of Cape Town and Swanage, U. K., 1893 (Box 34, Folder 232)
      - Jarvis, A. Weston
        - Historical photographs of South Africa, Rhodesia; also photographs of Cecil Rhodes and Emperor Wilhelm [letter laid in], 1896-1908 (Box 35, Folder 233)
        - Mining properties in Rhodesia, military scenes at onset of Boer War, 1899-1900 (Box 36, Folder 234)
        - Boer War [includes Rustenberg, Shashi River, Groote Schuur, the Rhodes's farm, important military locations; presumably belonging to Jarvis], Circa 1899-1902 (Box 37, Folder 235)
        - Boer War [Elandsfontein, Standerton, Heidelberg], 1901 (Box 38, Folder 236)
        - Boer War [including the capture of General Erasows?, battle-fields, concentrations camps, peace conference], 1902 (Box 39, Folder 237)
        - "South Africa: 1910" [photographs of Rhodesia, Westminster, Pretoria, Cape Town] (Box 40, Folder 238)
      - "Boer War Photographs" [field photographs of British soldiers during Boer War], 1899-1902 (Box 41, Folder 239)
      - Banner, Harmood, "4th South Wales Borderers" [photographs and ephemera relating to service in the Boer War: Orange River Colony, Transvaal; includes travel tickets, typescript, military orders, menus, maps, etc.], 1899-1902 (Box 42, Folder 240)
      - Jack, J. L., "South African War, 1902 Apr- Jun" [2nd lieutenant in Scottish Horse regiment], 1902 April-June (Box 43, Folder 241)
      - Taylor, D., "Souvenir of the Siege of Mafeking", 1899-1900 (Box 43, Folder 242)
      - Boer War [3rd Lincoln Regiment in South Africa], Circa 1902 (Box 44, Folder 243)
      - South African scenery [two loose photos laid in including one depicting the shooting of Matabele spies], [ca. 1902?] (Box 44, Folder 244)
      - "The British Association Meeting" [souvenir album from 1905 meeting; Cape Town, Groote Schuur, Bloemfontein, Rhodesia] (Box 45, Folder 245)
      - British military photographs [Cape Town, Bloemfontein, Pretoria, etc.], [ca. 1907?] (Box 46, Folder 246)
      - World War I [scrapbook compiled by William Jardine, a British officer in German Southwest Africa; photographs, clippings, and several posters], 1913-1917 (Box 47, Folder 247)
      - Album of a visit to South Africa and return voyage [photographs taken on board the S. S. "Nestor" and the S. S. "Ascanius," also photographs of various locations in South Africa], 1929 (Box 48, Folder 248)
      - Souvenir album from a three-month vacation in South Africa [Cape Town, Devil's Peak, Table Mountain, Rhodes Memorial, Groote Schuur], 1934 (Box 48, Folder 249)
      - Queenstown, South Africa [mostly family portraits and greeting cards, some of Queenstown, Scotland and England], undated (Box 49, Folder 250)
      - Reynolds, Alexander, photographs of natives and wildlife from southern and central Africa [2 volumes], undated (Box 51, Folder 252, Box 50, Folder 251)
- Additional Material, Accession 1998-M-087
  - Hutton, Edward T. H.
    - Bound volume of letters to his wife pertaining to his role as major general in the Boer War [includes photograph of Hutton and plans of operations; rear pocket contains "Briton or Boer: New Map of South Africa", 1900 March-October (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 1998-M-090
  - Murray, F. D.
    - "Extracts from Letters of Major F. D. Murray," [Murray was attached to Dundonald's Third Mounted Brigade], 1899 October 12-1901 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1900 January-December 31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, Accession 1998-M-131
  - Harmel, Michael
    - "The White People: A Satirical Fantasy" [photocopy of unpublished typescript], [195?] (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-063
  - Photograph albums
    - Muscutt, C. R., [photographer]
      - Trigonometrical survey of the Orange River, Transvaal colonies, and Basutoland [three albums], 1904-1905 (Box 1)
      - "Snapshots taken at Benoni, during my pleasant stay with my cousin, Charlie Adams" [2 albums], 1906 January (Box 1)
    - Unidentified reservist in the S. A. Air Force [photographer]
      - Life in South Africa during World War II [eastern Cape Province, Natal; includes loose photographs of the Xosa people], 1940-1941 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-077
  - Coke, Roger [aide-de-camp to Prince Arthur, Duke of Connaught]
  - Correspondence to/from the Department of Defence, pertaining to military equipment, such as mine sweeping vessels and aircraft, 1920 December- 1921 January (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Harvey, Gilbert R. [assistant surgeon at the Second Cavalry B ______ Field Hospital]
    - Diary in two volumes describing military skirmishes, camp conditions, and related topics, 1899 November- 1900 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nicholl, Hugh Iltid [commander of the Sixth Mounted Infantry Company of the Bedfordshire Regiment]
    - "A South African Journal, 1900" [privately published journal; includes one letter pertaining to the publication of journal and related topics], 1929, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-078
  - Durban Civic Centenary Celebration
    - Souvenir programs pertaining to theatrical productions; receptions and balls; art exhibits; concerts; agricultural and industrial fairs; air shows; and related events celebrating Durban's centenary, 1954 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-079
  - Photograph album [containing photographs of Victoria Falls and other points of scenic interest; natives; villages; cities; mining sites; and unidentified individuals], Circa 1920s (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-105
  - Facsimile edition set of three stone lithographs originally printed by MGL Germany during the Anglo-Boer War [artist unknown], 1988
    - "Guerre Sud-afric: Bataille de Stormberg" (Box 1)
    - "Guerre Sud-afric: La Prise de Gen Methuen" (Box 1)
    - "Guerre Sud-afric; Assaut de Spionskop" (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 2000-M-141
  - "The Defence of Rorke's Drift 22/23 January 1879" [a British Archives publication], [1980s] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brabourne, Lord. "The Truth about the Transvaal", 1881 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Railway Extension from Charlestown to Johannesburg; Copy of Agreements Between the Governments of Colony of Natal and the South African Republic, Dated 3rd and 12th February, and 25th April, 1894" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kolonialkriegerdank Kalendar f ü r das Jahr 1916 [annual edition by the charity helping war victims from the German colonies] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Union of South Africa. "Rules for the Financial and General Administration of Government Commissions and Committees", 1928 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Tours in South, Central and East Africa" [Thos. Cook & Son, Ltd.], [1930s] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - High Commission Territories in South Africa: Aide-mémoire handed to the Prime Minister of the Union of South Africa by the Secretary of State for Dominion Affairs on 15th May, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "The Kruger National Park" [issued by South African Railways, Airways and Harbours], 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The History of the United Africa Company Limited to 1938" (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Address delivered by The Honorable J. H. Hofmeyr on the Occasion of his Installation as Chancellor of the University of Witwatersrand Johannesburg", 1939 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Civil History of the War of 1939-1945 South African High Commission Territories" [Commonwealth Relations Office report] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Goofy," by Leyden [cartoons illustrating safe driving techniques, published by the Durban and District Road Safety Association], [1940s] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Twenty-four Views of Durban: The Playground of South Africa" [tourist brochure], [1940s] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Transvaal Land Owners' Association [includes constitution and newsletter], 1941, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "African Tribes Employed on the Witwatersrand Gold Mines", 1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Union of South Africa. Act No. 44, 1950 and Act No. 50, 1951 [documents pertaining to the Communist Party of South Africa], 1950, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Orchard, R. K. "The High Commission Territories", 1951 August (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Problem of Territories of Southern Africa" [published by the South African Institute of International Affairs], 1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Coronation brochures [celebrations in Durban for crowning of Elizabeth II], 1953 June (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Natal Society of Artists [program for the forty-eighth annual exhibition of South African contemporary art], 1953 July-August (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bantu Fair [program for exhibition of native dancing/arts and crafts], 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Union of South Africa [memoranda pertaining to the socio-economic development/self government of the Bantu areas], 1956, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "The High Commission Territories and the Union of South Africa" [distributed for the Royal Institute of International Affairs], 1957 April (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Old House Museum [guide to the historical collections], undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "South Africa" [tourist information], undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Le President Krueger" [handbill for film], undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Additional Material, Accession 2002-M-068
  Accession 2002-M-068 includes Accession 2002-M-069 and Accession 2002-M-070.
  - Nixon, A. C. [corporal in the 44th Battery, British Army] Diary [describing his voyage to South Africa, military training, personal injury, and combat in the Boer War; includes photograph of Nixon in uniform], 1900 January-1901 February (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Poster announcing a talk on the Boer War ["All Yale Men are Cordially Invited to Be Present"] [New Haven?], 1902 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miniature photographs of Port Alfred, South Africa [includes original wrapper, "Tiny Peeps"], undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, Accession 2004-M-051
  Files in this accession are listed alphabetically by type of material.
  - Correspondence
    - Buller, Redvers, general of British Army to officer commanding 2ndbatallion, Royal Scots Fusiliers [requesting accommodation and rations for three YMCA volunteers], 1899 December 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hatfield, Mercedes to unknown, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Rhodes, C. J. to Alfred Beit, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Smuts, Jan Christia[a]n to Albert Edward Phineas Robinson, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Printed materials
    - A Commentary on Politics Today [journal of the United Party, nos. 18 and 25], 1956 Nov, 1957 July (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Independent ,, vol. 1, no. 1, 1919 May (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ivy, J. R. (pty) ltd., High Art Taxidermist and Furrier [certificate for possessing game skins], 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Labour Party [election campaign flier], undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Legal Education Action Project (LEAP) [educational materials], undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - National News, vol. 1. no.1 [newspaper of the National Party], 1948 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Petition to the House of Commons [questions affecting the native subjects of His Majesty the King], 1906 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - United Democractic Front (UDF) [anti-apartheid posters], undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Western areas protest committee: displaced persons [flier], 1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Zabantsundu, Imro [invoice for subscription], 1889 December 21 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photographs
    - "Annexation of the Transvaal", 1877 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "Four Promising Subjects for Missionary Work", undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "Joseph Butterworth, the People's Outfitter Store", undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Smith, J. W. [private in British Army, 17th Lancers; photograph and diary], 1900 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified postcard and letter, 1905, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Additional Material, Accession 2003-M-048
  - Fifty-two glass slides on the Boer War [mostly war scenes but nine are of portraits and seven are scenes in South Africa], [ca. 1902?] (Box 1)
  - Fifty-two glass slides on the Boer War [mostly war scenes but nine are of portraits and seven are scenes in South Africa], [ca. 1902?] (Box 2)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-050
  Files in this accession are listed alphabetically by author/title/organizational name.
  - Die Afrikaanse gids van organisasies, nr. 5, 1959/1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Castle Line Royal Mail [handbook of information for passengers between London and Southhampton and the South African gold fields], 1897 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Council for Coloured Affairs, Union of South Africa [report], 1959 December 14 - 1961 December 31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Gresley, G. F., "The Early History of Robben Island" [reprinted from the Illustrated Magazine ], undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hotrchefstroomse Universiteit [commemorative program], 1951 March 14-17 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Instituut vir Christelik-Nastionale Onderwys [van die F. A. K], 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Official documents concerning South Africa [translation from The White Book, 16th vol, Berlin], 1896 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Reports dealing with the subject of returned soldiers and the assistance granted to them [Sep 1, 1918 - Dec 31, 1919] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Routh, Guy, South Africa, the facts [a Union of Democratic Control publication], undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Rural research" [progress report], 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - South Africa (Naval Brigade) ["copies of despatches in regard to the Naval Brigade in South Africa, which were published in the London Gazette of the 12th instant"], 1901 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - South Africa (unwounded soldiers dead or invalided home) ["Return of the number of officers and men who since the commencement of the war have died or been invalided home from cause other than wounds received in action"], 1900 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Stellenbosch Public Library, 1859-1959, 1959 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Teachers' Journal [organ of the Natal Indian Teachers' Society], 1956 July (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "The Work of the Wage Board" [report to theHonourablethe Minister of Labour by the Wage Board], 1929 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Unity in Service: the Story of Red Cross in South Africa", undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - University of the Witwatersrand, 1957 May (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-060
  - The Graphic, "The Capture of Sekukuni's Stronghold—General View of the Attack, 10 a.m., Nov. 28, 1879 ", 1880 January 24 (Folder 1)
  - The Illustrated London News
    - "The Zulu War: The Intrenched Position at Rorke's Drift" [in supplement], 1879 March 8 (Folder 1)
    - "The Zulu War: The Laager Method of Defence", 1879 April 5 (Folder 1)
    - "The Zulu War: Dabulamanzi, Brother of King Ceteway, Commander of the Zulu Army at Islandhlwana", 1879 April 12 (Folder 1)
  - South Africa Review, vol. 45, no. 1230 [a wartime copy of South Africa's oldest weekly journal, 22 pages], 1915 December 17 (Folder 1)
  - Die Zeit von 1870-1914, Ruhmesblütter Deutscher Geschichte [sticker collection], undated (Folder 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-064
  The accession contains guide books, pamphlets, and an itinerary for travel in South Africa, including rail and cruise information. Many of the books are produced by the Thos. Cook & Son travel service.
  - General information, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Travel guides
    - 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1938, [ca. 1951] (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Travel itinerary [arranged by Thos. Cook & Son for Mr. & Mrs. Frank Tuthill], 1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional Material, Accession 2006-M-017
  - Flag of the Orange Free State, Circa 1880 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Circa 1885-1950; Accession 2011-M-041
  Arrangement
  The accession is arranged in alphabetical order by type of material.
  - Legal document
    - British South Africa Company and Yeta and Members of the Barotse Council and Others: Agreement As to Minerals and Reserved Area in North-Western Rhodesia, 1938 August 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Maps
    - Lots for sale in 1887 Johannesburg, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Reproduction printed on back of paper advertisement for The Guildhall Pub & Restaurant (probably used as a placemat).